49. The Shakespeare of Rock and Roll.
In 2016, a songwriter won the Nobel Prize in Literature for the first time.
But this is only the latest victory for the man often called the greatest American poet of the 20th century.
Ladies and gentlemen, meet Bob Dylan.
Born in Minnesota in 1941, Robert Zimmerman changed his name and moved to New York in 1961 to make a career in music.
Originally a folk singer, he played social and political songs in coffee shops for small crowds.
He was soon noticed by Columbia Records, and his first album, Bob Dylan, was released in 1962.
Although his early records weren't very big sellers, Dylan quickly found success as a songwriter.
His famous protest song, Blowing in the Wind, was a hit for the folk trio Peter, Paul and Mary in 1963.
Since then, countless other artists have covered Dylan's songs.
In 1965, Dylan shocked the music world by switching from soft folk to hard rock.
While some of his old fans were disappointed, many new fans were created.
The single, like a rolling stone, reached number two in the United States, making Dylan a star.
A couple of years later, he changed styles again, writing and playing quiet country songs.
Now the rock fans were upset, but Dylan just kept moving forward.
1969's Nashville Skyline was as fast as selling album yet.
The end of the 1960s did not bring an end to Dylan's success.
Hits such as Knockin' on Heaven's Door, 1973, kept him in the public eye,
and 1975's Blood on the Tracks remains his best-selling album.
More than 40 years later, he continues to record and perform around the world.
In addition to his Nobel Prize, Dylan has won 12 Grammy Awards, an Academy Award,
and the U.S. Presidential Medal of Freedom.
The man who began his career by attacking the establishment is now very well established.